watchtvb.com 2019-04-23

# 私隱聲明 Privacy Policy

## 私隱聲明

1\. 本聲明僅適用於您透過使用TVB Anywhere網站（www.tvbanywhere.com）（「服務網站」）或您使用及/或登記TVB Anywhere Limited（「我們」）提供的TVB Anywhere服務（「服務」）時，不時向我們提交或我們不時向您所收集的個人資料。

2\. 本聲明已被納入並構成我們的服務條款的一部分。透過向我們提交可直接或間接地識別您或其他個人的資料（「個人資料」），即表示您了解並同意本聲明。我們會定期檢視本聲明，並不時在服務網站上發布本聲明的任何更改。如您在我們更新本聲明後繼續使用服務及/或服務網站，即表示您同意受該更新版本的條文約束。因此，請您定期瀏覽服務網站以參閱本聲明的最新版本。有關無綫電視集團如何管理您的個人資料的信息，請參閱corporate.tvb.com/html/privacy.html上的隱私政策條款和細則。就本聲明而言，「無綫電視集團」指電視廣播有限公司年報中列明的無綫電視集團公司。

3\. 對香港以外用戶的重要提示：如果您是服務網站和/或服務的非香港用戶，並透過瀏覽服務網站或使用服務向我們提供個人資料，您即確認並同意該等個人資料可就本聲明所指定的目的被處理。此外，個人資料可在收集國家和其他國家（包括香港）處理，而處理個人資料的地方法律可能不如您所屬國家的法律嚴格。通過提供個人資料，您明確表示同意該等轉讓。

個人資料的收集

4\. 我們以自願、公開和公平的方式收集您的個人資料。我們亦會在您使用服務網站及/或服務時，收集您使用服務網站及/或服務的相關信息。

5\. 我們或會向您收集的個人資料包括（a）當您註冊成為服務的會員或要求/購買我們的產品或服務時所提供的資料，包括您的姓名、電郵地址、電話號碼、地址或郵政編碼、付款方式，及其他讓我們能提供服務的必要資料；（b）您在使用服務網站及/或服務時向我們提供的資料；（c）有關您的電腦、電話或其他啟用互聯網設備（統稱為「設備」）的資料，該等資料或包括流動應用程式編碼、瀏覽器的類型和配置、語言設定、設備的地理位置和位置、設備類型/製造商、互聯網規約（IP）地址（和域名）、操作系統類型和版本、網絡類型和互聯網服務供應商；和（d）有關您使用服務網站和/或服務的資料，其中或會包括瀏覽網頁的時間/持續時間或所使用的服務（瀏覽紀錄）。

6\. 您可能偶爾需要向我們提供有關其他個人的個人資料。 在每次上述的情況下，您必須遵守香港法例第486章《個人資料（私隱）條例》（「條例」），並在使用和向我們披露和轉讓該等個人資料前以作相關目的前，先取得相關人士的授權（包括代表他們同意我們或會對其個人資料的使用、披露和轉讓）。我們或會要求您向我們提供任何可證明上述授權的所需證明文件。您亦應告知相關人士，可與我們聯絡以了解詳情。

個人資料的使用

7\. 您提交個人資料，純屬自願性質。您有權拒絕提供任何個人資料，但若您未能提供充份資料，我們或許未能向您提供服務或其任何部分。

8\. 您所提供的個人資料將會用於以下目的及其他與以下目的相關及/或為促進以下目的的其他目的（統稱「該等目的」）：  
(a) 我們經營的網絡平台及應用程式的相關活動；  
(b) 提供服務；  
(c) 申請、執行、繼續及終止服務的使用；  
(d) 確定您的一般地理位置，以便我們可以為您提供定制、個性化、本地化的內容、建議、功能和在服務內或外的廣告；  
(e) 為進行及完成您要求的交易；  
(f) 促進您和我們之間的溝通，以便我們向您發送有關服務的最新消息，包括服務新功能和內容的詳細資料;  
(g) 在符合您向我們表示之任何許可的情況下，透過電郵、短訊或其他訊息，直接或透過我們的關聯公司或合作夥伴與您通訊，以進行營銷和促銷活動；  
(h) 進行信用審查；  
(i) 處理結算和付款、確定未清金額；如有必要，向您收取未付款項；  
(j) 使您能夠日常操作和管理與服務相關的會員帳戶；  
(k) 處理和跟進服務電話、查詢和投訴；  
(l) 核實您的身份；  
(m) 使我們能夠遵守互連的義務和其他行業慣例；  
(n) 符合任何適用的法律、政府或法規要求，包括我們所受制的任何披露或通知要求；  
(o) 使我們能夠為您在不同地點、設備、連接和情況下提供最有效的服務；  
(p) 就我們提供的服務進行研究；  
(q) 使我們能夠更了解用戶的人口統計；  
(r) 對我們提供的任何服務或產品的行為和興趣進行統計分析  
(s) 在適用法律允許的範圍內，直接促銷我們的服務，及通知您關於推廣、特別優惠或新產品的信息；  
(t) 任何其他您不時同意的目的。

9\. 您保證：（a）向我們提供真實的、準確的、實時的及完整的個人資料；及（b）不時更新上述資料。如我們懷疑您違反本條款，我們有權暫停或終止您的用戶帳號或拒絶您登入服務或其任何部份，而毋須另行通知。

10\. 如我們認為有需要向您提出任何行動（包括但不限於向您追討欠款或其他原因），您明確同意我們可以依據您提供的個人資料來作識別您的身份及向您提出法律訴訟之用。

直接促銷

11\. 我們擬使用您的個人資料（包括您的姓名、電話號碼、電郵地址以及服務使用記錄）作直接促銷有關於我們、無綫電視集團和我們的業務夥伴或會提供的以下類別產品和服務：  
(a) 與我們和/或無綫電視集團及/或我們的業務夥伴有關或提供的產品、服務、新聞、獎勵、促銷和活動；  
(b) 與商戶和商業夥伴聯合推廣，為服務的會員提供折扣和其他福利；  
(c) 有關娛樂、媒體和公共關係、電訊、移動語音、短信和數據通信、國際漫遊、互聯網連接、流動應用和軟件、電腦配件、生活方式、時尚飾物、電子、電子商務、音樂、遊戲、零售、休閒運動、食品飲料、體育活動和會員、水療休閒活動、家居、服裝、交通運輸和旅遊、軟件和遊戲、教育、環境、健康及保健、非營利、信息技術、社會網絡、育兒、金融和地產、以及高端消費品的產品和服務。

12\. 上述直接促銷可能由我們及/或：  
(a) 無綫電視集團內的任何公司；  
(b) 我們的業務夥伴提供第11（c）項條款所述的產品和服務；  
(c) 我們或無綫電視集團或我們的商業夥伴的代理人提供上述產品和服務。  
為此目的，我們所持有在第11項條款所述的的個人資料可能會為得益而提供予本項所述的所有或任何人士，以供他們在直接促銷該等產品和服務時使用。

13\. 除非獲得條例的許可或我們已取得您的同意（包括表示不反對該項使用或提供），否則我們不得如此使用或提供您的個人資料。

14\. 如果您與任何時候希望我們停止使用和提供個人資料作直接促銷，您可以向我們發送電郵（請列明您的用戶名稱和電郵地址），並選擇不繼續接收無綫電視集團有關公司及/或我們業務合作夥伴的材料或通信。

披露  
15\. 我們將採取實際及合理的措施保護您的個人資料，免被未獲授權人士或第三方意外取得、公開、誤用、處理、更改、銷毀或遺失，惟我們或會轉移/轉讓該等資料予以下人士：  
(a) 當我們決定出售任何相關的業務部份時，任何與該等資料有關的權利的實際或準受讓人、承讓人或繼承人；  
(b) 任何為我們提供本服務或與本服務有關的行政、電訊、電腦及其他服務的代理、供應商、承辦商、專業顧問、保險商、其他網絡營運者或第三方服務供應商；  
(c) 所有我們基於法律要求或按執法機構或其他政府部門及監管機關的要求而須將該等資料予以披露的相關人士；  
(d) 所有為協助我們進行偵察、調查、防止或其他針對欺詐、保安或技術問題的第三方或政府機關。

16\. 我們也可能在下列情況向第三方披露您的個人資料：（i）法律規定、法院命令或回應搜查令或其他有法律效力的查詢時；或（ii）根據我們的信念相信法律要求披露或以其他方式設立法律訴訟或辯護、獲取法律諮詢、行使和維護我們的合法權利或有必要保護任何個人的性命、身體或財產時。 當我們有理由相信披露個人資料是必要，以對有可能導致我們的權利或財產受干擾（不論故意與否）的人或任何其他有可能因該等干擾而受到損害的人作出識別、聯絡或法律行動。

17\. 如我們被牽涉任何涉及全部或部分公司重組或其他公司控制變更的合併或出售，我們或會轉讓我們持有關於您的任何資料作為與合併或銷售有關的資產（包括作為破產或破產程序一部分的轉移）。

18\. 如有需要，我們或會將您的個人資料轉移到香港以外地區，為執行收集個人資料的該等目的（或與該等目直接相關的目的）。我們將按照例條的要求進行該等轉移。

COOKIES檔案

19\. COOKIES是當您瀏覧服務網站時貯存於您的裝置的微型測試檔。COOKIES檔案可用於識別裝置，但不是用於收集服務網站個別用戶的個人資料。COOKIES檔案所收集的資料為匿名的集體資料搜集數據，不會包含姓名或地址或任何可至使他人通過電話、電郵或其他方法聯繫到您的資料。有些COOKIES檔案是服務網站所要求您處理的；而有些COOKIES檔案則為提供予您更佳、更個人化的瀏覽體驗。雖然瀏覽器自動接受COOKIES檔案，但您可編輯您的瀏覧選項以拒絕COOKIES檔案。但您或因此而不能使用服務網站的部份功能或不能登入服務網站部份範圍。透過使用服務網站，即代表您允許我們使用COOKIES檔案。

個人資料的安全

20\. 除第15至18項條款的情況外，您的個人資料只有我們授權的員工或承辦商才可處理。該等授權的人士只會於遵守本聲明的情況下方會被指派處理個人資料。我們已使用合理的保安措施以確保您的個人資料不會在未經授權下被披露、取得、使用及/或更改。請注意，雖然我們克盡己力，但沒有保安措施是完美或無法破解的，亦沒有任何可保證百份百安全的互聯網傳輸。

個人資料的貯存

21\. 我們會貯存您的個人資料直至收集個人資料的該等目的達成為止。其後，除非有關貯存是為符合法例、法規或會計的要求或為保護我們的權益，我們會銷毀該等資料。

個人資料的索取及更生

22\. 您可隨時：  
(a) 要求索取並更正於我們所記錄關於您的個人資料；  
(b) 要求我們從任何郵寄或發佈清單上刪除您的個人資料；  
(c) 停止使用您的個人資料及按服務條款停止使用服務。

23\. 如您須行使上述權利，或對我們對私隱的慣常做法有任何疑問，請透過以下地址（註明您的用戶名稱和電郵地址）與我們聯絡：  
TVB Anywhere Limited  
香港九龍將軍澳工業邨  
駿才街七十七號電視廣播城  
我們回覆時或會要求您提供更多關於您的資料，以確保您為該等個人資料指明的人士。我們或會因應您的要求向您徵收合理費用。

第三方網址的連結

24\. 服務網站和服務可能包括指向其他服務或網站的連結。本聲明僅適用於服務網站和服務。當您進入連結網站或其他服務時，您將暴露於非由我們負責的COOKIES檔案。您提交給連結網站或其他服務的任何資料將受到該等網站或服務的私隱政策（如有）的約束。您在向相關連結網站或服務提供任何資料前，務必小心查閱相關政策。

一般條款

25\. 除您的個人資料外，所有經電郵發送給我們的訊息，均不會被視為或視作保密訊息處理。請您不要以電郵形式向我們發送任何您認為屬於機密的資料、意見、提議、想法或批評，或您希望保密處理的資訊。

26\. 您與我們員工的通話內容或會被錄音，而我們或會於不另行通知的情況下使用該等錄音作為證據。

27\. 若本聲明的任何部份被視為不合法或由於任何原因無法執行，該部份將被視為與本聲明分割，而本聲明的所有其餘條款的有效性及可執行性均不受其影響。

28\. 本聲明受香港特別行政區的法例管轄及根據香港特別行政區的法例闡釋。香港特別行政區的法院對本聲明的爭議有非專屬司法管轄權。

29\. 本聲明以英文撰寫，並可能被翻譯成其他語言。 如本聲明的英文版本與翻譯版本有任何歧異，概以英文版本為準。

最後更新日期：2017年4月19日

## **PRIVACY STATEMENT**

1\. This Privacy Statement applies only to information submitted and collected through your use of our website[www.tvbanywhere.com](http://www.tvbanywhere.com/) (“ **Service Website** ”) or your registration and use of the services (“ **Service** ”) provided by TVB Anywhere Limited (“ **we** ”, “ **us** ” or “ **our** ”) from time to time.

2\. This Privacy Statement is incorporated into and forms part of our Terms of Use. By submitting to us data that may directly or indirectly identify you or other person(s) as an individual (" **personal data** "), you understand and agree to this Privacy Statement. We regularly review this Privacy Statement and will post on the Service Website any changes to this Privacy Statement. By continuing to use our Service after any amendments to this Privacy Statement, you are agreeing to be bound by the Privacy Statement as revised, so please do visit the Service Website periodically for updates. Please also refer to the terms and conditions of the Privacy Policy as set out on [ http://corporate.tvb.com/html/privacy.html ](http://corporate.tvb.com/html/privacy.html) for information about how the TVB Group manage your personal data. For the purpose of this Privacy Statement, “TVB Group” refers to the companies in the TVB Group as set out in the annual report of the Television Broadcasts Limited.

3\. **AN IMPORTANT NOTE TO USERS OUTSIDE OF HONG KONG**. If you are a non-Hong Kong user of the Service Website and/or the Service, by visiting the Service Website or using the Service and providing us with personal data, you acknowledge and agree that such personal data may be processed for the purposes identified in this Privacy Policy. In addition, the personal data may be processed in the country in which it was collected and in other countries, including Hong Kong, where laws regarding processing of personal data may be less stringent than the laws in your country. By providing the personal data, you expressly consent to such transfer.

### COLLECTION OF PERSONAL DATA

4\. We collect your personal data on a voluntary, open and fair basis. Information relating to your use of the Service Website and/or the Service will also be collected from you when you use the Service Website and/or the Service.

5\. Personal data that we may collect from you includes (a) information you provide when you register to be a member of the Service or request/purchase a product or service from us including your name, email address, telephone number, address or postal code, and payment method, with other data necessary for the provision of our Service; (b) information you provide to us when you use the Service Website and/or the Service; (c) information about your computer, phone or other web enabled device (collectively, the “ **Device** ”), which may include mobile app token, the types and configurations of browsers, language settings, geo-location and location of your device, device type/manufacturer, Internet Protocol (IP) address (and domain names), operating system type and version, network type, and Internet service providers; and (d) information about your usage of the Service Website and/or the Service, which may include the time/duration and the pages visited or the services used (access log).

6\. You may occasionally need to provide personal data about other individual(s) to us. In each of such event, you are required to comply with the Personal Data (Privacy) Ordinance (Cap. 486 of the Laws of Hong Kong) (“ **Ordinance** ”) by first obtaining the authorization of such individual(s) before using, disclosing and transferring their personal data to us (including giving consent on their behalf to our possible use, disclosure and transfer of their personal data) for the relevant Purposes. We may require you to provide us with any supporting documents which may be necessary to prove such authorization. You should also advise such individual(s) that we can be contacted for further information.

**USE OF PERSONAL DATA**

7\. It is entirely voluntary for you to provide personal data. Whilst you are entitled to refuse providing any of the personal data, incomplete disclosure may prevent us from rendering the Service or any part thereof to you.

8\. Personal data provided by you will be used by us for the following purposes and any purposes related to and/or for the furtherance of any of these purposes (collectively “ **Purposes** ”):

(a) activities relating to the Internet web portal and applications operated by us;

(b) enabling the provision of the Service;

(c) application, administration, continuation and termination of the use of the Service;

(d) determining your general geographic location, so that we can provide you with customized, personalized, localized contents, recommendations, features and advertising on or outside of the Service;

(e) processing and completing transactions requested by you;

(f) facilitating communication between you and us, so that we can send you news about the Service including new features and content available on the Service;

(g) communicating with you, either directly or through one of our affiliates or partners, for marketing and promotional purposes via emails, notifications, or other messages, consistent with any permissions you may have communicated to us;

(h) conducting credit reference checks;

(i) processing billing and payment, determining amounts outstanding, and, if necessary, collection of outstanding payments;

(j) enabling the daily operation of and managing your membership accounts in relation to the Service;

(k) handling and following up service calls, enquiries and complaints;

(l) verifying your identity;

(m) enabling us to comply with our obligations to interconnect and other industry practices;

(n) meeting any applicable legal, governmental or regulatory requirements including any disclosure or notification requirements, to which we are subject to;

(o) enabling us to provide you with the most effective service in different locations, devices, connectivity and situation;

(p) conducting research in relation to the Service provided by us;

(q) enabling us to better understand the demographics of our users;

(r) performing statistical analysis of your behavior and interest in any service or products provided by us;

(s) to the extent permissible under applicable laws, direct marketing of our Service, notifying you of promotion, special offers or new products information; and

(t) any other purposes as may be agreed by you from time to time.

9\. You warrant to: (a) provide us true, accurate, current and complete personal data about yourself; and (b) update the foregoing data from time to time. We may suspend or terminate your membership account or refuse your access to the Service or any part thereof without notice or liability if we suspect that you have breached this provision.

10\. If it becomes necessary that we have to take action against you for any reason whatsoever including without limitation recovering from you any money you owe us, you expressly agree that the personal data provided by you can be relied upon in identifying and taking legal action against you.

### DIRECT MARKETING

11\. We intend to use your personal data (including your name, telephone numbers and email address, and record of use of the Service) for direct marketing in relation to the following classes of products and services that we, the TVB Group, and our business partners may offer:

(a) products, services, news, rewards, promotions and events related to or offered by us and/or the TVB Group and/or our business partners;

(b) joint promotion with merchants and business partners offering discount and other benefits to members of the Service;

(c) products and services on entertainment, media and public relations, telecommunications, mobile voice, SMS and data communications, IDD/Roaming, Internet connectivity, mobile applications and software, computer peripheral, lifestyle, fashion and accessories, electronics, e-commerce, music, gaming, retail, leisure and sports, food and beverage, sports activities and membership, spa and relaxation activities, household, apparel, transportation and tourism, software and games, education, environmental, health and wellness, non-profit, information technology, social networking, parenting, financial and property, and high-end consumer products.

12\. The above direct marketing may be conducted by us and/or:

(a) any of the companies within the TVB Group;

(b) our business partners providing the products and services set out in paragraph 11(c) above;

(c) by an agent on behalf of us or the TVB Group or our business partners providing the aforesaid products and services.

For such purposes, your personal data held by us described in paragraph 11 above may be provided to all or any of the persons described in this paragraph for gain for use by them in marketing those products and services.

13\. We may not so use or provide your personal data unless exempted from the Ordinance or we have received your written consent (which includes an indication of no objection).

14\. If you wish to withdraw your consent to the use and provision of your personal data for direct marketing at any time, you may opt-out of receiving such materials or communications from the relevant member of TVB Group and/or our business partners by writing a request to us together with your user name and email address.

### DISCLOSURE

15\. While we will take all practicable and reasonable steps to protect personal data from unauthorized or accidental access, disclosure, misuse or processing, or from alteration, destruction or loss, we may transfer and/or disclose such data to the following parties for the Purposes as set out in this Privacy Statement:

(a) our employees and officers;

(b) any actual or proposed assignee, transferee or successor of or to our rights in respect of your personal data if we decide to sell any relevant part of business;

(c) any agent, supplier, contractor, professional advisor, insurer, other network operator or third party service provider who provides administrative, telecommunications, computer and other services to us and/or the relevant service(s) in connection with the Service;

(d) any person to whom we are under an obligation to make disclosure under the requirement of any law binding on us or for the purposes of any guidelines or codes of practice issued by regulatory or other authorities with which we are expected to comply;

(e) any other person or company who is under a duty of confidentiality to us and has undertaken to keep such information confidential, provided such person or company has a legitimate right to such information.

16\. We may also disclose your personal data to third parties: (i) when required by law, by court order or in response to a search warrant or other legally valid inquiry; or (ii) pursuant to our good faith belief that disclosure is required by law or otherwise necessary to the establishment of legal claims or defences, to obtain legal advice, to exercise and defend our legal rights or to protect the life, body or property of any individual. This also applies when we have ground to believe that disclosing the personal data is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing interference with our rights or properties, whether intentionally or otherwise, or when anyone else could be harmed by activities causing such interference.

17\. We may also transfer any information we hold about you as an asset in connection with a merger or sale (including transfers made as part of insolvency or bankruptcy proceedings) involving all or part of a corporate reorganization or other change in corporate control.

18\. If necessary, we may transfer your personal data to places outside Hong Kong for carrying out the Purposes (or the directly related purposes) specified above, for which the personal data were collected. Where such a transfer is performed, it will be done in compliance with the prevailing requirements of the Ordinance.

### **COOKIES**

19\. Cookies are small bits of information that are automatically stored on your device when you visit the Service Website. A cookie can be used to identify a Device, but it is not used to collect personal information of an individual user of the Service Website. The information collected by “cookies” is anonymous aggregated research data and contain no name or address information or any information that will enable anyone to contact you via telephone, e-mail or any other means. Some of the cookies are required by the Service Website to enable you to transact whilst other cookies enable us to give you an enhanced, personalized browsing experience. Whilst most web browsers automatically accept cookies, you can edit your browser options to block them. However, if you do so, you may not be able to use some of the functions or access certain areas of the Service Website. By using the Service Website, you consent to the use of these cookies.

### SECURITY OF PERSONAL DATA

20\. Except as provided in paragraphs 15 to 18 above, your personal data will be accessed only by our employees or contractors who are authorized to do so. Employees and contractors designated to handle personal data will be instructed to do so only in accordance with this Privacy Statement. We have implemented reasonable security measures to safeguard your personal data from unauthorized access, disclosure, use and modification. Please be aware, however, that despite our efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable, and no transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure.

### RETENTION OF PERSONAL DATA

21\. We will retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfill the Purposes for which such personal data was collected. We will then destroy such data unless their retention is required to satisfy legal, regulatory or accounting requirements or to protect our interests.

### ACCESS TO AND UPDATE OF PERSONAL DATA

22\. You are entitled at any time to:

(a) request access to and correct personal data relating to you in any of our records;

(b) ask us to remove your personal data from any active mailing or distribution list; or

(c) cease to use your personal data and terminate your use of the Service subject to our Terms of Use.

23\. To exercise any of your foregoing rights, or if you have questions regarding our privacy practices, please contact us together with your user name and email address at the following address:

TVB Anywhere Limited  
TVB City, 77 Chun Choi Street  
Tseung Kwan O Industrial Estate  
Kowloon, Hong Kong

In response, we may ask you to provide certain details about yourself so that we can be sure you are the person to whom the personal data refers. We may charge you a reasonable fee for processing such access requests.

### **LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES**

24\. The Service Website and the Service may include links to other services or sites. This Privacy Statement applies to the Service Website and the Service only. You are exposed to cookies that are not our responsibility when you access to linked sites or other services, and any information you submit to linked sites or other services will be subject to the privacy policies of those sites or services (if any). You are advised to review the relevant policies carefully before providing any information to those linked sites or services.

### GENERAL

25\. All information other than the personal data that you send through to any of our email addresses will not be considered or treated as confidential information. Do not send us through email any information, ideas, suggestions, proposals or comments that you consider confidential or that you want to be treated as confidential.

26\. Your telephone conversations with our staff may be recorded and used as evidence by us without further notice.

27\. If any part of this Privacy Statement shall be deemed unlawful or for any reason unenforceable, then that provision shall be deemed to be severable from this Privacy Statement and shall not affect the validity and enforceability of any of the remaining provision of this Privacy Statement.

28\. This Privacy Statement shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of Hong Kong SAR. Disputes arising herefrom shall be subject to the non-exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of Hong Kong.

29\. This Privacy Statement is written in English language and may be translated into other languages. In the event of any inconsistency between the English version and the translated version of this Privacy Statement, the English version shall prevail.

Last Update: 19 April 2017
